Guide to the University Archives photograph collection, 1861-ongoing UA.01.15.0009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Buildings Series, 23 Boxes, approx. 11,500 items
  - Mary Duke Biddle Music Building (Box 95)
  - Mary Duke Biddle Music Building [Dedication, Color Prints and Negatives] (Box 95)
  - Mary Duke Building, Trinity College [Women's Dormitory] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Aerial Views] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Architectural Sketches and Artwork] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Baker House, Nurses] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Bell (Research) Building] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Chapel] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center, 1966 [Construction] (Box 95)
  - Medical Center [Davison Building] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Davison Building, Library and Trent Room] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Davison Building, Construction] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Duke Building] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Eye Center] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hanes House, Construction] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hanes House ] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hanes House Annex] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hart Pavilion] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hospital Laundry, Construction] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hospital North] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hospital South, Exterior] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hospital South, Aerial] (Box 96)
  - Medical Center [Hospital South Construction and Additions] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Hospital South Interior] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Hospital South Snapshots] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Hyperbaric Unit] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Isolation Facility] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Jones, Edwin L., Cancer Research] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Lab/Classroom] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Library, Old] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Library, Seeley-Mudd Community Center] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Nanaline H. Duke Building] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Pickens Building] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Polio Ward] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center, 1967 [OB Gyn Ward] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [Nursing School] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center, 1939-1940 [Private Diagnostic Clinic, Construction] (Box 97)
  - Medical Center [PRT (People Mover)] (Box 97)
  - Mordecai House, Trinity College (Box 97)
  - Morris Building, 1978 [Tour, Dedication] (Box 97)
  - North Building (Box 97)
  - Nuclear Laboratory (Box 97)
  - Orange Presbytery, Central Campus [Construction] (Box 97)
  - Orr, Louis [Etchings] (Box 97)
  - Page Auditorium (Box 98)
  - Pegram Dormitory (Box 98)
  - Pegram House, Trinity College, Faculty Row (Box 98)
  - Physics Building (Box 98)
  - Physics Building [Construction] (Box 98)
  - Physical Plant (Box 98)
  - Phytotron (Box 98)
  - Phytotron, 1967 [Construction], 3 folders (Box 98)
  - Phytotron, 1969 (Box 98)
  - Plaque of the "Aims of Duke University" (Box 98)
  - Post Office (Box 98)
  - Pre-fabricated Houses (Box 98)
  - President's House, Trinity College (Box 98)
  - President's House [First in Durham, Original Faculty Row House] (Box 98)
  - President's House (New) (Box 98)
  - Primate Center (Box 98)
  - Psychiatric Clinical Training Building (Box 98)
  - Residential College, East Campus, 1986-1988 [Attempt] (Box 98)
  - Rigsbee Cemetery (Box 98)
  - Sea Level Hospital (Box 98)
  - Snow Scenes (Box 98)
  - Social Science Building (Box 98)
  - Sociology - Psychology Building (Box 98)
  - Southgate Hall (Box 98)
  - Stagg Pavilion (Box 99)
  - Statue: Benjamin Newton Duke (Box 99)
  - Statue: J.B. Duke (Box 99)
  - Statue: James B. Duke (Box 99)
  - Statue: James B. Duke, 1935 [Installation and Unveiling] (Box 99)
  - Statue: The Sower (Box 99)
  - Statue: Washington Duke (Box 99)
  - Stonemasonry - Hillsborough [West Campus Construction (Allen Building)] (Box 99)
  - Sundial, Trinity College (Box 99)
  - Tel-Com Building (Box 99)
  - Trent Hall (Box 99)
  - Triangle Universities Nuclear Lab (TUNL) (Box 99)
  - Trinity College Historical Society Museum (Box 99)
  - Trinity Park School [See also Asbury Building] (Box 99)
  - Union, East Campus (Box 99)
  - Union, West Campus [Exterior] (Box 99)
  - Union, West Campus [Interior, Including Dope Shop, Book Store] (Box 100)
  - Union, West Campus [Construction] (Box 100)
  - Vesic Library (Box 100)
  - Wallace Wade Stadium [Construction, Renovation] (Box 100)
  - Wallace Wade Stadium [Crowd Scenes] (Box 100)
  - Wallace Wade Stadium [Aerial Views] (Box 100)
  - Wannamaker Hall (Box 100)
  - Washington Duke Building, Trinity College (Box 100)
  - West Campus Views, 1954 (Box 100)
  - Washington Duke Inn (Box 100)
  - West Campus Quadrangle (Box 100)
  - West Duke Building (Box 100)
  - West Edens Link Dormitory, 2003 (Box 100)
- Separated Photographs Series, 23 Boxes
  - Buck, Robert - Photograph Collection (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers, Photographs, 2 folders (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers, Photographs [Durham Cathedral, England] (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [Mt. Athos] (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [Mosaic Depiction of Jerusalem, St. Catherine's Monastery] (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [St. Catherine's Monastery, Mt. Sinai], 3 folders (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [Illustrations] (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [Greece, Armenia, Jerusalem] (Box 101)
  - Clark, Kenneth W. Papers [Photographic identifications, Miscellaneous] (Box 101)
  - Gray, Irving E. (Zoology) [Slides], 2 folders (Box 101)
  - Kulski, W.W. Papers [Photographs] (Box 102)
  - Margolis, Reuben, 1926-1929 [Campus Construction Photographs] (Box 102)
  - Russell, Mattie U. Papers [Photographs] (Box 102)
  - Unidentified Activities / Groups (Box 102)
  - James L. Oswald (Box 102)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1980-1982 [Kim Sanders], 3 folders (Box 102)
  - "The Dukes of Durham," Pace Magazine, 1968 (Box 102)
  - Knell, Charles E., [approximately 30 photographs of Duke University buildings], 1930s (Oversize-box 103)
  - Duke Presidents (Oversize-box 104)
    - John C. Kilgo (Oversize-box 104)
    - William P. Few (Oversize-box 104)
    - Robert L. Flowers (Oversize-box 104)
    - Arthur H. Edens (Oversize-box 104)
    - Nannerl O. Keohane (Oversize-box 104)
  - People (Oversize-box 105)
    - Bonk, James (Chemistry), circa 1964 (Oversize-box 105)
    - Bowling, Edgar S. (President of Alumni Association, 1932-1933) (Oversize-box 105)
    - Branson, Anna (Mrs. J.A. Thomas) (Oversize-box 105)
    - Duke, James B., 1923 + 1 negative (Oversize-box 105)
    - Duke, Washington, undated (Oversize-box 105)
    - Hickman, Frank, Boston School of Theology class of 1920 (Oversize-box 105)
    - Kenan, William R. (Oversize-box 105)
    - Miller, Justin, Law School Dean (Oversize-box 105)
    - Myers, H.E., Boston School of Theology class of 1920 (Oversize-box 105)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (4) (Oversize-box 105)
    - Rankin, Professor Robert S., April 25, 1975 (Oversize-box 105)
    - Raper, Charles Lee (Oversize-box 105)
    - Unidentified, Law School dean or faculty member, April 1949 (Oversize-box 105)
    - Upchurch, Walter McGowan (Oversize-box 105)
    - Womble, Bunyan Snipes, Chairman Board of Trustees, 1960-1963 (Oversize-box 105)
  - Trinity College Class Photos, 1895-1918 (see also MC_2) (Oversize-box 106-107)
  - Trinity College Sports (Oversize-box 108)
    - Basketball, 1910-1920 (3) (Oversize-box 108)
    - Baseball, 1897-1914 (16)
      - Randolph County (NC) baseball team, undated (Oversize-box 108)
    - Football
      - First football team, c. 1890 (Oversize-box 108)
      - Southern Champions, 1981 (Oversize-box 108)
    - Gymnastic Class, 1904, 1912, undated (includes 1 negative) (Oversize-box 108)
    - Tennis Team, undated (2) (Oversize-box 108)
  - Trinity College Student Groups and Activities (Oversize-box 109)
    - 9019 (see also MC_2)
      - Group pictures, circa 1897-1909, undated (12) (Oversize-box 109)
  - Trinity College Student Groups and Activities (Oversize-box 110)
    - Chronicle editorial staff composites, 1921-1922 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Chronicle staff, 1908-1912 (Oversize-box 110)
    - College band, 1916 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Columbian Society, 1910 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Deutscher Verein, 1910 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Duke's Mixture, 1910 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Editorial staff of the Archive, 1886-1887 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Marshals and managers, 1909, undated (Oversize-box 110)
    - Sigma Phi Epsilon, NC Gamma Chapter, 1915 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Student group, undated (Oversize-box 110)
    - Tombs, 1907-1920 (6) (Oversize-box 110)
    - Trinity College Historical Society, 1912 (Oversize-box 110)
    - Trinity College (Randolph County, NC) student group, undated (Oversize-box 110)
    - Unidentified men's group, undated (2) (Oversize-box 110)
    - Washington, DC trip, 1898 (2) (Oversize-box 110)
  - Trinity College faculty (Oversize-box 111)
    - LaPrade, William Thomas, 1913 (Oversize-box 111)
    - Pegram, W.H., (2) plus 1 negative (Oversize-box 111)
    - Trinity College faculty
      - 1891-1892 (Oversize-box 111)
      - 1899-1900 (2) (Oversize-box 111)
      - 1900-1901 (Oversize-box 111)
      - 1904 (4) plus 1 negative (Oversize-box 111)
      - 1906 (Oversize-box 111)
    - Wolfe, James Jacob, Professor of Biology 1904-1920 (Oversize-box 111)
  - Trinity Park High School (Oversize-box 112)
    - Asbury, circa 1936-1938 (Oversize-box 112)
    - Baseball team, undated (Oversize-box 112)
    - Bivins, Joe, Headmaster of Trinity Park High School (Oversize-box 112)
    - Calhoun, John C., Calhoun Literary Society, pre-1903 (Oversize-box 112)
    - Graduating Class, 1903 (Oversize-box 112)
    - Senior class, 1906 (Oversize-box 112)
    - Trinity Park High School, undated (Oversize-box 112)
    - Trinity Park High School, 1899 (Oversize-box 112)
  - Campus (Buildings and Landscaping) (Oversize-box 113)
    - (Old) Alspaugh, (2), undated (Oversize-box 113)
    - Chapel, interior, circa 1965 (Oversize-box 113)
    - Craven Memorial Hall, undated (3) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Epworth Inn, undated (5) (Oversize-box 113)
    - James B. Duke Statue (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Memorial Hall Library, North Dormitory, undated (Oversize-box 113)
    - Page Auditorium, Gothic Bookshop, circa 1965 (Oversize-box 113)
    - Paul M. Gross Chemical Laboratory (Oversize-box 113)
    - Southgate, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Trinity Gate, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Trinity College campus scenes, undated (15) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Trinity College Library, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Washington Duke building, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Washington Duke building and Trinity Gate, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
    - Washington Duke statue, undated (2) (Oversize-box 113)
  - Professional Schools (Oversize-box 114)
    - School of Engineering
      - Faculty (4) (Oversize-box 114)
    - School of Forestry
      - Analysis of wood preserving compound (Oversize-box 114)
      - Barkbeetle studies (Oversize-box 114)
      - Faculty composite (Oversize-box 114)
      - Glue bond quality research (Oversize-box 114)
      - Growth and yield studies (Oversize-box 114)
      - Kiln drying research (Oversize-box 114)
      - Tropical woods research (Oversize-box 114)
      - Vapor drying research (Oversize-box 114)
  - Aerial and Construction photos of Duke University campus, Durham, and Henderson, NC (Oversize-box 115)
    - Aerial Photos
      - Duke University construction, circa 1928-1929 (Oversize-box 115)
      - East Campus, undated (2) (Oversize-box 115)
      - East Campus, circa 1950 (Oversize-box 115)
      - Golf Course, c. 1957 (Oversize-box 115)
      - Southern Aerial Survey Henderson, NC (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, undated (8) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, circa 1939, 1940 (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, circa 1940, 1950, 1968 (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, Chapel (9) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus construction, circa 1930 (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, Medical Center (3) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, Science Drive, undated, 1968 (3) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus, Science Drive and Towerview (2) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Durham, circa 1972-1974 (Oversize-box 115)
    - Construction
      - Bryan Center, ground breaking (Oversize-box 115)
      - East Campus, circa 1925 (2) (Oversize-box 115)
      - West Campus (Oversize-box 115)
  - Fraternities (see also MC_2) (Oversize-box 116)
    - Kappa Alpha, circa, 1894-1910; 1980 (9) (Oversize-box 116)
  - Fraternities and Honor Societies (see also MC_2) (Oversize-box 117)
    - Alpha Tau Omega, undated, 1940-1944, 1953 (6) (Oversize-box 117)
    - Kappa Sigma, 1907-1908 (Oversize-box 117)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1995 (Oversize-box 117)
    - Phi Kappa Phi, undated (Oversize-box 117)
    - Pi Kappa Alpha, 1918 (Oversize-box 117)
  - Duke University, activities (Oversize-box 118)
    - Alumni Dinner Dance, New York City, 1936 (Oversize-box 118)
    - Drama
      - The Intellectual Ladies, 1973 (4) (Oversize-box 118)
      - The Madwoman of Chaillot, 1972 (1) (Oversize-box 118)
      - After the Fall, 1974 (Oversize-box 118)
      - The Tempest, 1972 (Oversize-box 118)
      - Blithe Spirit, 1974 (Oversize-box 118)
      - J.B., 1972 (Oversize-box 118)
      - He Who Gets Slapped, October 1991 (Oversize-box 118)
      - Cymbeline, April 1992 (Oversize-box 118)
      - WPF (Mask of the Oyama), February 1992 (Oversize-box 118)
      - Three Cuckolds, November 1991 (Oversize-box 118)
    - Student life, circa 1950, 1960, 1964 (Oversize-box 118)
    - White Duchy, 1960-1965 (4) (Oversize-box 118)
  - Duke University, activities (Oversize-box 119)
    - Drama, continued
      - The Birthday Party, 1975 (Oversize-box 119)
      - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1975 (Oversize-box 119)
      - The Hotel Baltimore, 1975 (Oversize-box 119)
      - A Streetcar Named Desire, 1973 (Oversize-box 119)
  - Football, 1931-1942 (Oversize-box 120)
  - Football, 1943-1950 (Oversize-box 121)
  - Duke University Libraries (Oversize-box 122)
    - Libraries Employees, 1976 (21) (Oversize-box 122)
    - Knight, Douglas M., National Library Commission (Oversize-box 122)
    - DULSA (Duke University Library Staff Association), Christmas party photo album, December 18, 1985 (Oversize-box 122)
    - Powell, Benjamin E., Retirement photo album (Oversize-box 122)
  - Hauptfuhrer, Barbara Barnes Photograph Collection (Oversize-box 123)
    - Clippings, 1947; 1949 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Claudio Arrau, pianist (Oversize-box 123)
    - J. Foster Barnes and Nelson Eddy (Oversize-box 123)
    - Lucille [Browning?], 1944 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Noble Cain, sacred mucis composer (Oversize-box 123)
    - Mischa Elman, 1936 (Oversize-box 123)
    - (Dorothy Fields?), an English soprano pictured with Duke student John Alexander (Oversize-box 123)
    - Mary Garden, 1931 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Lansing Hatfield, Governor Broughton, Evelyn Case, J. Foster Barnes, 1941 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Jascha Heifetz, 1943 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Joseph Hoffman (Oversize-box 123)
    - Vladimir Horowitz, pianist (Oversize-box 123)
    - Jose Iturbi, pianist (Oversize-box 123)
    - Doris Kenyon (Oversize-box 123)
    - Reank Laforge (Oversize-box 123)
    - Luboshutz and Nemenoff, duo-pianists (Oversize-box 123)
    - Edwin McArthur (Oversize-box 123)
    - Yehudi Menuhin (Oversize-box 123)
    - Charles Meunch, conductor (Oversize-box 123)
    - Nathan Milstein, violonist (Oversize-box 123)
    - Dimitri Mitropoulos, 1948 conductor Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra (Oversize-box 123)
    - Grace Moore (Oversize-box 123)
    - Eugene Ormandy, 1940 (Oversize-box 123)
    - Paderewski (Oversize-box 123)
    - Ezio Pinza (Oversize-box 123)
    - Rachmaninoff (Oversize-box 123)
    - Artur Rubinstein, pianist (Oversize-box 123)
    - Russian Cosack Dancers (Oversize-box 123)
    - Carlos Salzedo (Oversize-box 123)
    - Rudolf Serkin (Oversize-box 123)
    - Eleanor Steber, soprano (Oversize-box 123)
    - Leopold Stokowski, conductor (Oversize-box 123)
    - Ferrucio Tagliavini, leading tenor (Oversize-box 123)
    - Blanche Thebom, mezzo-soprano (Oversize-box 123)
    - Lawrence Tibbet (Oversize-box 123)
    - Helen Traubel (Oversize-box 123)
    - Richard Tucker (Oversize-box 123)
  - Nancy Hanks, oval portrait taken in France A85-26 (Box 124)
  - Allen, G.G., portrait printing plate (Box 124)
  - Drawing for proposed expansion of Trinity College, Randolph Co., circa 1870s (Box 124)
  - "Trinity Guard," circa 1863 (Box 124)
  - James Burrus Collection (Box 125)
    - Chapel (Box 125)
    - Dormotories, West Campus (Box 125)
    - Robert L. Flowers (Box 125)
    - Schools and Academic buildings, West Campus (Box 125)
    - Union (Box 125)
  - Classes, Class of 1909, Album c.2 (Box 126)
  - Stutts, DeWitt Talmage (Trinity 1915) Collection (Box 126)
  - Class of 1906 (Album) Duplicate (Box 126)
  - East Duke Parlor – Renovations, 1987 (Box 126)
  - Reception for R Taylor Cole, 1988 (Box 126)
  - Nannerl Keohane and Deborah Jakubs Trip to Chile, 2011 (Box 126)
  - Charles Wesley Clay Photographs, circa 1928-1929 (Box 126)
    Scope and Contents note
    Largely images of construction of West and East Campuses, including the football stadium. Also includes photographs of commencement, the Duke Marching Band, and May Day festivities.
  - Robert Page Photographs, circa early 1940's (Box 126)
    Four black/white images from a football game in the early 1940's. Two are action shots, one is an image of the audience, focusing on a man (possibly Page's uncle Hugh) and a woman, and one is of a female Duke cheerleader, the Duke mascot, and a young boy on the sideline.
  - Joel Sandulli Photographs, 1957-1962; 7 items (Box 126)
    Seven color 35mm slides of the Duke campus and nearby area. Description given by Joel Sandulli.
    - A. Joel Sandulli '57 standing where the terrace of the Washington Duke Inn is today - the golf course was just being cut out of the forest., circa 1957 (Box 126)
    - B. The same place as A., circa 1957 (Box 126)
    - C - F. Joe College floats in front of East Campus, circa 1957-1959 (Box 126)
    - G. Richard Sandulli '62 with his future wife on West Campus for a concert - Joe College., circa 1962 (Box 126)
  - Lewis Wardell Photographs, 1970-1993
    - Student demonstration, May 1970 (Box 126)
    - Sinkhole on Flowers Drive, Spring 1984 (Box 126)
    - Police Headquarters on Oregon St, circa 1993 (Box 126)
  - Panoramic images: Students of Trinity College, 1912-1913 and Campus of Trinity College, 1912-1913 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Hiking Club Group Portrait, 1924 (from Chanticleer, p. 179) (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Perkins Library, undated (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Portrait of William G. Anlyan, M.D., undated (UA2004-55) (Oversize-folder 4)
  - Portrait of H. Keith H. Brodie, 1981 (UA2004-55) (Oversize-folder 5)
  - Portrait of [James H. Southgate?], undated (Oversize-folder 6)
  - Portrait of Washington Duke, undated (Oversize-folder 7)
  - Panoramic of Faculty and Trustees of Trinity College, Durham, undated (identified) (Oversize-folder 8)
  - Portrait of John O. Blackburn, undated (UA2004-55) (Oversize-folder 9)
  - Portrait of A. Kenneth Pye, undated (UA2004-55) (Oversize-folder 10)
  - Portrait of Barnes Woodhall, 1969 (UA2004-55) (Oversize-folder 11)
  - Composite: Chi Delta Phi, 1970-1972 (UA85-43) (Oversize-folder 12)
  - Dick Groat and Dave Sime photograph (UA2019.0082), circa 1950s (Box 126)
    Photograph taken by Robert (Robin) Blake, T'67. Also included is a typed manuscript by Robin Blake describing the circumstances around the photograph and giving biographical details for both Dick Groat and Dave Sime.
  - Aerial photographs of West Campus, reproductions (UA2014.0054), circa 1930s-1940s (Box 126)
    Donated by Arthur S. Gould, class of 1944. Original images date from circa 1930s-1940s, these photographs reproduced circa 2000s.
  - Photographs of East Campus construction, circa 1925; 4 items (Box 126)
    Photographs donated by Gerret Warner, relative of Frank Warner. Photographs were found in Frank Warner's belongings, but it is unknown if he was the photographer.
  - Francis "Bud" Marion Rodgers, III, photographs, 1937-1940 (Box 126)
    Includes photographs of production of Iolanthe (1938), Duke/Tennessee football game (1938), West Campus(1940), Sigma Nu, Gamma Chapter (1940), and other photos of students and places. A number of photographs identify individuals and organizations.